{"status":"Success","data":{"general_datas":[{"q_number":"26","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d7c\u0d36\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d "},{"q_number":"27","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d7c\u0d36\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"1895 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d 22"},{"q_number":"28","question":"\u0d06\u0d27\u0d41\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d21\u0d47\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d "},{"q_number":"29","question":"\u0d06\u0d27\u0d41\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d09\u0d2a\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7e ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d32\u0d42\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d30\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c(\u0d06\u0d17\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d24\u0d4d\u200c \u0d32\u0d42\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7c, \u0d32\u0d42\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d32\u0d42\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7c)"},{"q_number":"30","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d36\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d0e \u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d1f\u0d41 \u0d2e\u0d42\u0d7a (\u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02-\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d46\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d ,1902 )"},{"q_number":"31","question":"\u0d15\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d21\u0d4d\u200c\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d. \u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7c "},{"q_number":"32","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d42\u0d7a \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d3f "},{"q_number":"159","question":"\u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e: \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d38\u0d41\u0d30\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"190","question":"\u0d28\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"191","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d24\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\r\n"},{"q_number":"192","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4a\u0d7b\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d25\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d23\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d35\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d02"},{"q_number":"193","question":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d37\u0d40\u0d32\r\n"},{"q_number":"194","question":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n\r\n","answer":"\u0d05\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"195","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d2c\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d\r\n"},{"q_number":"196","question":"\u0d2c\u0d37\u0d40\u0d7c \u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d25 \u0d0e\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\r\n","answer":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d17\u0d35\u0d40\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"197","question":"\u0d2a\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d32 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d17\u0d40\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d12\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?\r\n\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d02"},{"q_number":"198","question":"\u0d09\u0d7e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d1f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d7b?\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d1c\u0d3f.\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d1c\u0d4d\r\n"},{"q_number":"199","question":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?\r\n\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d28\u0d38\u0d40\u0d24"},{"q_number":"200","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f.?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\r\n"},{"q_number":"201","question":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d32 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d30\u0d1a\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d3f.\u0d36\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d\r\n"},{"q_number":"202","question":"\u0d13\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d.\u0d38\u0d47\u0d24\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d35\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"203","question":"\u0d38\u0d42\u0d2b\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e \u0d15\u0d25 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d7b?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"204","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d0e\u0d02.\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d47\u0d16\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\r\n"},{"q_number":"205","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d07\u0d1f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d47\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d38\u0d3f.\u0d35\u0d3f.\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"206","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2c\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d15\u0d24\u0d3f ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d07\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d28\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"207","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d30\u0d35\u0d40\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d7b (\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f )\r\n"},{"q_number":"208","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f.\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c \u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e \u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d02?\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\r\n"},{"q_number":"209","question":"\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c?\r\n","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d02.\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\r\n"},{"q_number":"210","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40?\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d47 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\r\n"},{"q_number":"211","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d7b?\r\n","answer":"\u0d05\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b \r\n"},{"q_number":"212","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d40\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e? \r\n","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d2c\u0d31\u0d3f\r\n"},{"q_number":"213","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15?\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d32\r\n"},{"q_number":"214","question":"\u0d2e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d1f \u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d23\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02, \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"215","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f?\r\n","answer":"\u0d05\u0d1f\u0d42\u0d7c \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"216","question":"\u0d1a\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d15\u0d35\u0d3f?\r\n\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"217","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d2b\u0d46\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?\r\n","answer":"\u0d37\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d3f.\u0d0e\u0d7b.\u0d15\u0d30\u0d41\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"218","question":"\u0d12\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?\r\n","answer":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41\r\n"},{"q_number":"219","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d7c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d02? \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d41\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?\r\n","answer":"1969, \u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d38\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d35\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"220","question":"\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d15 \u0d15\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d7b.\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d30\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"221","question":"\u0d07\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d28\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d02\r\n","answer":"\u0d05\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2c\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d\r\n"},{"q_number":"222","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d07\u0d1f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e\r\n","answer":"\u0d38\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d3f.\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"223","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d -\u0d1c\u0d46 \r\n","answer":"\u0d38\u0d3f \u0d26\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d7d\r\n"},{"q_number":"224","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e -\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d17\u0d24\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"225","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d06\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f -","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d2e(1933)\r\n"},{"q_number":"226","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d36\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d26 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d7b(1938)\r\n"},{"q_number":"227","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02\r\n\u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f -","answer":"\u0d06\u0d32\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\r\n\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d (\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d7b 1938)"},{"q_number":"228","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02\r\n\u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d -","answer":"\u0d39\u0d32\u0d4b \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c\r\n"},{"q_number":"229","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d7b -","answer":"\u0d15\u0d46\r\n\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d30\u0d42\u0d7c\r\n"},{"q_number":"230","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f -\r\n","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"231","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d7c \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d2c\u0d46\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d(1961)\r\n"},{"q_number":"232","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d26 (1941)"},{"q_number":"233","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2c\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d39\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24 \u0d28\u0d57\u0d15 (1951)\r\n"},{"q_number":"234","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d2c\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d (1955)\r\n"},{"q_number":"235","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d24\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41 (1978)\r\n"},{"q_number":"236","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f 70mm \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 (1982)"},{"q_number":"237","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\r\n\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d30\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d7d-","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4c\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\r\n\u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b\r\n"},{"q_number":"238","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f 3D \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d48 \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d7b (1984)\r\n"},{"q_number":"239","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d2c\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4a \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f (1996)\r\n"},{"q_number":"240","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d3f \u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d47\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d38\u0d4d(2000)\r\n"},{"q_number":"241","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1c\u0d28\u0d15\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e -","answer":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e \u0d05\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7b\r\n( 1986)\r\n"},{"q_number":"242","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f sponsered \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e -","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d7e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d4d\r\n(2005)\r\n"},{"q_number":"243","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e -\r\n","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d42\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4a\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7e (2006)\r\n"},{"q_number":"244","question":"\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d14\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d4b\u0d7c \u0d7d\r\n\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e-","answer":"\u0d13\u0d33\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 (1970)\r\n"},{"q_number":"245","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d46\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d46\u0d21\u0d7d\r\n\u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d40\u0d32\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d (1954)\r\n"},{"q_number":"246","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d23 \u0d2e\u0d46\u0d21\u0d7d\r\n\u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 -","answer":"\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"247","question":"\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\r\n\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f -","answer":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7c\r\n"},{"q_number":"248","question":"\u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\r\n\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\r\n\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02-","answer":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41 (1997)\r\n"},{"q_number":"249","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b -","answer":"\u0d09\u0d26\u0d2f (1948)"},{"q_number":"250","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4a\u0d38\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f -\r\n","answer":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d32\u0d47\u0d16 (1964)\r\n"},{"q_number":"251","question":"\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40 \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d7b -\r\n","answer":"\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d36\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d41\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d7c(1973)\r\n"},{"q_number":"252","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1c\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d3f \u0d21\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d -\r\n","answer":"\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d07 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d41\u0d26\u0d47\u0d35\u0d7b (1992)"},{"q_number":"253","question":"\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d26 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d46\u0d2c\u0d4d \u0d2b\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\r\n\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f _","answer":"\u0d05\u0d1f\u0d42\u0d30\u0d4d \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"254","question":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f\r\n\u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d -","answer":"\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d7b (1965)\r\n"},{"q_number":"255","question":"\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d0e.\u0d2c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c\r\n"},{"q_number":"256","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d25 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d47\u0d32\u0d30\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02\r\n"},{"q_number":"257","question":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d15\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f.\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"258","question":"\u0d2e\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d24\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d10\u0d38\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"259","question":"\u0d2e\u0d34 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d25?\r\n","answer":"\u0d28\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d28\u0d40\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d30\u0d3f, \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\r\n"},{"q_number":"260","question":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d30\u0d41\u0d23 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d24\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"261","question":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?\r\n","answer":"\u0d1f\u0d3f.\u0d2a\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d7b\r\n"},{"q_number":"262","question":"\u0d26\u0d48\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d32\u0d46\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"263","question":"\u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d25 ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41 \u0d2d\u0d42\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e"},{"q_number":"264","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d30 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d25?","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d25."},{"q_number":"265","question":"\u0d2a\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d32 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d17\u0d40\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d02"},{"q_number":"266","question":"\u0d36\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3e \u0d24\u0d30\u0d7a \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d42\u0d32\u0d15\u0d25 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d7b\u0d2e\u0d30\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e \u0d35\u0d40\u0d34\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e - \u0d0e\u0d7b.\u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d.\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d35\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"267","question":"\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"268","question":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d17\u0d35\u0d40 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d2c\u0d37\u0d40\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d25 ?","answer":"\u0d28\u0d40\u0d32\u0d35\u0d46\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d02"},{"q_number":"269","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f 70mm \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02?","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02"},{"q_number":"270","question":"in which Annie gives it those \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d05\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"271","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d1a\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"272","question":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d2c\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d41\u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e"},{"q_number":"273","question":"\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d06\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d25 ?","answer":"\u0d1f\u0d3f.\u0d2a\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d46.\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d7b \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d42\u0d7c \u0d0e\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02"},{"q_number":"274","question":"\u0d1c\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d09\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"275","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e - \u0d15\u0d23\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d7b \u0d24\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"276","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d39\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d02.\u0d0e\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"277","question":"\u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d0e\u0d7b.\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"278","question":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d7b \u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d30\u0d1a\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d1a\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15."},{"q_number":"279","question":"\u0d12\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40 \u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24' \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7e"},{"q_number":"280","question":"\u0d38\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d06\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d38\u0d16\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"281","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02. \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d37\u0d40\u0d32"},{"q_number":"282","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d13\u0d17\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7c&\u0d32\u0d42\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"283","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d05\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d7d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d0e \u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"284","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d06\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d21\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d48\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d(1897)"},{"q_number":"285","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d36\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d26 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7c(1927)"},{"q_number":"286","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02\r\n\u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d05\u0d7d \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d4d(\u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7c 1927)"},{"q_number":"287","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02\r\n\u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d0e \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"288","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d7b ?","answer":"\u0d05\u0d7d \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"289","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d2c\u0d47\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d47\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"290","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d7c \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d32\u0d48\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d48\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d(1903)"},{"q_number":"291","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d13\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d40 (1911)"},{"q_number":"292","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f industry \u0d39\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d2c\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d28\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b (1915)"},{"q_number":"293","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d12\u0d36\u0d47\u0d37\u0d28\u0d46 (1943)"},{"q_number":"294","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d2c\u0d4d (1953)"},{"q_number":"295","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f 70mm \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d12\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d2e (1955)"},{"q_number":"296","question":"\u0d12\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d2e \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\r\n\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d30\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7b \u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7d ?","answer":"\u0d12\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d2e"},{"q_number":"297","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f 3D \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d35\u0d7c \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d35\u0d4d (1922)"},{"q_number":"298","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d2c\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4a \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d0e \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d (1971)"},{"q_number":"299","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d3f \u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d(1993)"},{"q_number":"300","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d12\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d09\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7a \u0d0e \u0d1f\u0d48\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d7b \u0d2e\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b (2001)"},{"q_number":"301","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d4d \u0d21\u0d3f \u0d14\u0d7c\r\n\u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d2a\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d (1939)"},{"q_number":"302","question":"\u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c\r\n\u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"303","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b ?","answer":"\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f (1893)"},{"q_number":"304","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4a\u0d38\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d32\u0d46\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d1f\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e (1930)"},{"q_number":"305","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d21\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d47 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d38\u0d46\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d21\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d47 (1952)"},{"q_number":"306","question":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d2e\u0d3f\r\n\u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d (1927)"},{"q_number":"307","question":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d1c\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d(\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d32\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d -1928)"},{"q_number":"308","question":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c\r\n\u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d ?","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d46\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d17\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d7c (1927)"},{"q_number":"309","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d7b ?","answer":"\u0d21\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d7d \u0d21\u0d47 \u0d32\u0d46\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d "},{"q_number":"310","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d13\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d\r\n\u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d39\u0d46\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d\u200c\u0d7c\u0d28\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"311","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d\r\n\u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d7b ?","answer":"\u0d12\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d7c \u0d39\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"312","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d\r\n\u0d05\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f ?","answer":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"313","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d\r\n\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e -\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c ?","answer":"\u0d39\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d7c\u0d1f\u0d4d\r\n,\u0d2c\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d21\u0d47\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"314","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d32\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d:\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d47\u0d7a \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"315","question":"\u0d0e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\r\n\u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7b ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d47\u0d33\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"316","question":"5 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d2c\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d28\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"317","question":"40 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d57 \u0d35\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d46\u0d35\u0d7b \u0d26\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"318","question":"30 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d17\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d47 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"319","question":"100 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"320","question":"200 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d15\u0d47\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\r\n\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d1f\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d "},{"q_number":"321","question":"\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d47 \u0d32\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"322","question":"\u0d2c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d7c"},{"q_number":"323","question":"\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d32\u0d4d&\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d2f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"324","question":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d17\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d2c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d7c \u0d2e\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"325","question":"\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d7e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"326","question":"\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d17\u0d31\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d17\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d7a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"327","question":"\u0d39\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d4d \u0d2d\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d7c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d39\u0d48 \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7c\u0d31"},{"q_number":"328","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d39\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d35\u0d48\u0d7d\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d47\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"329","question":"\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d39\u0d41\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d7a \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d37\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d57\u0d7a"},{"q_number":"330","question":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d08\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d0e\u0d35\u0d47\u0d31\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d47 \u0d2c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d42\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"331","question":"\u0d2e\u0d7c\u0d32\u0d4a\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"332","question":"\u0d05\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4b \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d06\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d7c \u0d13\u0d7e"},{"q_number":"333","question":"\u0d39\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d13\u0d7a \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d21\u0d7b \u0d2a\u0d4a\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"334","question":"\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d32\u0d48\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d48\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"335","question":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d2c \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"336","question":"\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d46\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d16\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d31\u0d3f"},{"q_number":"337","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d2b\u0d4d\u200c\u0d31\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"338","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d46\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ","answer":"\u0d13\u0d35\u0d7c \u0d26\u0d3f \u0d1f\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"339","question":"\u0d05\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d37\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d47\u0d17\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d38 \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d30\u0d57 \u0d21\u0d40\u0d7d"},{"q_number":"340","question":"\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d7e\u0d21\u0d7b \u0d10"},{"q_number":"341","question":"\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d4b \u0d21\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3f \u0d07\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d2f\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7b"},{"q_number":"342","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d21\u0d40\u0d38\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?","answer":"\u0d2b\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d&\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d38\u0d4d"},{"q_number":"343","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f 100 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e ?","answer":"\u0d1c\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d "},{"q_number":"627","question":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d\u0d35\u0d40\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d02\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d06\u0d28\u0d4d\u200d\u0d39\u0d46 \u0d16\u0d4b\u0d30\u0d46 \u0d26\u0d3e \u0d26\u0d28\u0d4d\u200d (\u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d3f )\r\n"},{"q_number":"628","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d21\u0d47\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d (\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d3f)\r\n"},{"q_number":"629","question":"\u0d17\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d41\u0d32\u0d4d\u200d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d26\u0d47\u0d35\u0d42\u0d33\u0d4d\u200d (\u0d2e\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d20\u0d3f)\r\n"},{"q_number":"630","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u200d \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d2b\u0d46\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d46\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u200d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d30\u0d4d\u200d\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d05\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d37\u0d28\u0d4d\u200d \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d05\u0d2a\u0d4d (2010, 63-\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u200d)\r\n"},{"q_number":"631","question":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d30\u0d41\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33 ?\r\n","answer":"\u0d1f\u0d4a\u0d31\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4b \u0d05\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33 (TIFF)\r\n"},{"q_number":"632","question":"\u0d1f\u0d4a\u0d31\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4b \u0d05\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d1a\u0d32\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d ?\r\n","answer":"1976\u0d32\u0d4d\u200d"}]},"code":"100"}